noddle.co.uk 2012-01-05

# Privacy Policy - Noddle

##  About Callcredit 

Callcredit is committed to the responsible, secure and safe management of consumer data for the purpose of credit referencing, risk assessment and providing electronic proof of your identity. As such, we will check the details you provide with fraud prevention agencies and share your information with them if we suspect a fraud. We may suspect fraud if you provide false or inaccurate information and we will keep a record of this. 

Callcredit is mindful of the importance of upholding the security of information under our control. All data collected through the Noddle website located at [www.noddle.co.uk](http://www.noddle.co.uk/) ('Website') that is stored electronically, is stored on secure servers, and we have stringent security and confidentiality procedures covering the storage and disclosure of such information, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

The following Privacy Policy forms part of the Noddle terms and conditions and will help you to understand how your personal information collected during your use of the Website will be treated by us. 

We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of your personal information. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any personal information you disclose on-line. You accept the inherent security risks of providing information and transacting over the Internet, and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security, unless this is due to our negligence or wilful default. 

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, the data controller is Callcredit Limited t/a Noddle of One Park Lane, Leeds, West Yorkshire, LS3 1EP and the nominated representative is Head of Compliance. 

##  Consent 

You have consented to us using your credit report and personal information you have entered into the Website for such purposes as are necessary for us to provide the Services. 

In addition, unless you have opted out we will also provide your personal information (but not your credit report or the Confidence Rating) to our group companies and selected third parties for the purposes of marketing including bringing other suitable products and offers to your attention. 

If you wish to change your consent at any time please contact us at [contact@noddle.co.uk](mailto:contact@noddle.co.uk)

##  What personal information do we collect? 

We collect personal information in several ways from different parts of the Website. Any personal information we collect will be used by us strictly in accordance with current data protection legislation and this Privacy Policy. We will store the information we collect from you and hold it electronically or otherwise. 

##  Why do we collect your personal information?

We collect personal information from you for the following reasons: 

  1. ###  Verifying your identity: 

We will collect information which will help us to verify your identity, such as email addresses, usernames and passwords, along with other personal information we will need in order to provide you with a copy of your credit file. This will include, for example, your name, date of birth, your residential address and postcode. This information will be checked against external databases, such as the electoral roll and your credit file, to which we have access for this purpose. We will collect and store a record of the check as well as any additional information you provide, including (but not limited to) aliases, previous addresses and financial associations. This information may be disclosed to authorised third parties through our credit referencing, fraud prevention, risk assessment and identification products. 

Occasionally we may ask you to provide documentation for the purpose of verifying your identity, such as utility bills or bank statements. This information will only be requested when we need to verify your current address and we will protect the privacy of such personal information. We store such documentation securely, and it will be destroyed once verification is complete. 

If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering. Law enforcement agencies may also access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example when: checking details on applications for credit and credit-related or other facilities; managing credit and credit-related accounts or facilities; recovering debt; checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; checking details of job applicants and employees. Please email us at [contact@noddle.co.uk](mailto:contact@noddle.co.uk) if you want to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies. We and other organisations may access and use from other countries the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies. 

Further details explaining how the information held by fraud prevention agencies may be used can be obtained by emailing us at [ contact@noddle.co.uk](mailto:contact@noddle.co.uk). 

  2. ###  Processing your requests:

As part of the Credit Report Services we will obtain electronic copies of your credit reference file from Callcredit Limited and this will be stored in a private area accessible by you as part of this service. 

Any e-mail or mobile telephone numbers provided to us will be recorded and used to communicate with you in connection with the Credit Report Services or queries concerning the data held within the credit reports. This information may be disclosed to authorised third parties through our credit referencing, fraud prevention, risk assessment and identification products. 

  3. ###  Confidence Rating Services: 

Noddle uses a third party supplier (the identity of which may change from time to time at Noddle’s discretion) to help it generate your Confidence Rating Service. The third party supplier acts as a data processor in accordance with instructions from Noddle. 

By requesting provision of the Confidence Rating Service, you consent to Noddle providing the third party with information that you have entered into the Noddle website, together with a copy of your credit file. The third party will process this information in accordance with instructions given by Noddle for the sole purpose of generating your Confidence Rating. 

The third party will (in conjunction with third party credit providers and information provided by them) analyse key elements of your credit file, in order to determine your current financial standing. The analysis of your credit file will be used by the third party to identify and rank product offers in order of appropriateness for your circumstances (but this does not necessarily guarantee that there will be appropriate product offers available to you). You will then have the opportunity to apply for the product directly with the third party credit provider should you choose to do so. 

If you choose to proceed to apply for a product from the ranked list of offers, the supplier you choose will carry out its own identification and credit checks as part of its ordinary application process. 

Please note your credit file will not be provided to any third party credit provider at any point during this process (unless you subsequently agree to this). 

Signing up to Noddle and procuring and regularly updating your Confidence Rating will not have an adverse impact on your credit standing. 

Please note that the provision of your information, including the credit report, to the third party is subject to the Noddle Terms and Conditions (“Terms and Conditions”). 

  4. ###  Monitoring the relevance of the Credit Report Services: 

In order for us to ensure that our service is user-friendly and to help improve the content and user experience of the Website, the Website automatically gathers information on the number of visitors and readership patterns of the different pages. This allows us to tailor the Website to match your interests and preferences better and understand who has visited which pages to determine the most popular areas of the Website. We may also collect cookies and IP addresses for system administration and to report aggregate non-personalised information to our business contacts, selected third parties, sponsors or advertisers (such as anonymous statistics related to the take up or use of services, or to patterns of browsing). 

##  What are "cookies" and how do we use them?

We use cookies to track and record your preferences and activity on the Website. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Cookies may allow us to make the Website more user-friendly, for example, permanent cookies allow us to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it every time you visit the Website. Please remember, cookies do not contain confidential information such as your contact details. 

If you wish, you can usually adjust your browser so that your computer does not accept cookies. Alternatively you can adjust your browser to tell you when a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. How you adjust your browser to erase cookies, stop it accepting cookies or to notify you of them will depend on the type of Internet browser programme your computer uses. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. 

Your browser also generates other information, including your IP address. An IP address is a set of numbers, which is assigned to your computer during a browsing session whenever you log on to the Internet. Your IP address is automatically logged by our servers and used to collect traffic data about visitors to our Website. We do not use your IP address to identify you personally. 

##  What information do parties other than Callcredit collect?

Some websites that have links to and from our Website from time to time may collect personal information about you when you access or utilise those links. We do not control the collection or use of such information, and the practices of those websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. 

Some websites that have links to and from our Website from time to time may also use their own cookies. We have no access to, or control over these cookies, and you are advised to check the cookie policies on such other websites. 

##  Who do we share your personal information with?

  1. ###  Necessary Disclosure: 

It is necessary to disclose your personal information to: 

    * employees and agents of Callcredit Limited for the purpose of administrating your accounts in relation to the Credit Report Services; 
    * organisations including financial services, insurance providers and credit and debt collection agencies who in turn may use some of the information to help to assess an individual for credit or for the prevention of identity fraud; and 
    * anyone who may take over the operation of the Website or who may purchase any or all of our assets, including your personal information (we will contact you using the details you provide if there is any change in the person controlling your information).

As a result of us disclosing your personal information to any of the parties mentioned above, your personal information may be held by us and additionally by the parties mentioned above. 

  2. ###  Third Party Disclosure: 

Please note that we may disclose your personal information: 

    * to our selected agents, sub-contractors and third party processing companies for the purposes of market research and for analytical and statistical purposes; 
    * the third party provider with which we work from time to time to produce your Confidence Rating; 
    * to any third party, but only to the extent that we are permitted to do so in accordance with the marketing consent given to us by you, or to the extent we are required to do so by law; 
    * to fraud prevention agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering if false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified. 
    * organisations including financial services, insurance providers and credit and debt collection agencies who in turn may use some of the information to help to assess an individual for credit or for the prevention of identity fraud. 

We will not disclose your personal information to anyone other than those parties set out within this Privacy Policy without your consent. 

##  Your Rights to see your personal data

You have the right to see the personal data (as defined in the Data Protection Act 1998) that we keep about you, on receipt of a written request, verification of your identity, and payment of a fee. If you are concerned that any of the personal information we hold on you is incorrect, please contact us at the address shown in the "Contact us" section below. 

##  Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may modify our Privacy Policy from time to time in our sole discretion. If so, we will post a revised version of this Privacy Policy on the Website. We urge you to check the Privacy Policy regularly to obtain the most up to date copy. Updated versions of our Privacy Policy will be effective immediately when they are posted on the Website. Where appropriate we will email you to inform you of changes to our Privacy Policy. 

##  Contact us 

If you have any comments or queries in connection with our Privacy Policy, please email [contact@noddle.co.uk](mailto:contact@noddle.co.uk). 

Last updated December 2011 

* * *
